Finding aid for the Xavier University Office of Undergraduate Admission Records
Xavier University Archives and Special Collections
Xavier University Office of Undergraduate Admission Records
1920-2015
Xavier University Archives and Special Collections Phone: 513-745-4821 http://www.xavier.edu/cm/archives
Xavier University (Cincinnati, Ohio). Office of Undergraduate Admission
2.3 linear feet (6 boxes)
This collection contains material on undergraduate admissions and the admission process at Xavier University. It includes viewbooks and other publications produced by the Office of Admission.
XUA-85
History of Office of Undergraduate Admission
The Office of Undergraduate Admission manages undergraduate admissions at Xavier University.
Scope and Content
This Admission Office collection consists of freshman enrollment statistics, admission records, lists, academic profiles, brochures and marketing materials.
Statement of Arrangement
The collection is divided into four series and two subseries, as follows: Series I. Freshman Enrollment Statistics, 1980-2010; Series II. Admission Reports, Correspondence and Statistics, 1960-2015; Series III. Lists and Profiles: Subseries 1. Incoming Freshman Lists, 1957-1974; Subseries 2. Freshman Class profiles, 1983-1992; Series IV. Brochures, Pamphlets, and Marketing Materials.
Related Material
XUA-86, Xavier University Office of the Registrar Records, Special Collections and University Archives, Xavier University, Cincinnati, Ohio.
Restrictions on Access
Some materials may have restricted access. Please contact the archives staff.
Accruals
XUA2017-003 (Welcome to Xavier pamphlet, 2006) XUA2017-001
Indexing Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the library's online public access catalog.
Subjects:
Universities and colleges--Ohio--Admission--Statistics; Xavier University (Cincinnati, Ohio)-- Students; Xavier University (Cincinnati, Ohio) -- Admission.
Detailed Description of the Collection
- Series I. Freshman Enrollment Statistics, 1980-2010
  - Freshman Enrollment Statistics, 1980-2010 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Series II. Admission Reports, Correspondence and Statistics, 1960-2015; 1971-1979
  - Reports, Correspondence, Statistics, 1960-1961 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Reports, Correspondence, Statistics, 1965-1968 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Reports, Correspondence, Statistics, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Reports, Correspondence, Statistics, 1972 January-April (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Reports, Correspondence, Statistics, 1972 May-August (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Reports, Correspondence, Statistics, 1972 September-December (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Reports, Correspondence, Statistics, 1973 January-June (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Reports, Correspondence, Statistics, 1973 July-December (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Reports, Correspondence, Statistics, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Reports, Correspondence, Statistics, 1975 January-June (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Reports, Correspondence, Statistics, 1975 July-December (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Reports, Correspondence, Statistics, 1976 January-June (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Reports, Correspondence, Statistics, 1976 July-December (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Reports, Correspondence, Statistics, 1977 January-June (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Reports, Correspondence, Statistics, 1977 July-December (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Reports, Correspondence, Statistics, 1978 January-June (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Reports, Correspondence, Statistics, 1978 July-December (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Reports, Correspondence, Statistics, 1979 January-August (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Reports, Correspondence, Statistics, 1990-2015, undated (Box 3, Folder 2)
    This folder has only a few documents from this time period.
- Series III. Lists and Profiles, 1957-1992
  - 1. Incoming Freshman Lists, 1957-1974
    - Lists of Incoming New Students, 1957-1960 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Lists of Incoming New Students, 1960-1974 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - 2. Freshman Class Profiles, 1983-1992
    - Academic Profile Data for Freshman Classes, 1983-1992 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Freshman Class of 1992: a Profile, 1992-1993 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Series IV. Brochures, Pamphlets, and Marketing Materials, 1928-2010
  In this series are found what are commonly known as campus viewbooks (also know by the alternate spelling view books) which give an overview of the university and its services.
  - Brochures, Pamphlets, Bulletins, Posters: 1920's and 1930's (Part 1), approximately 1928-1939 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Brochures, Pamphlets, Bulletins, Posters: 1920's and 1930's (Part 2), approximately 1928-1939 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Brochures, Pamphlets, Bulletins, Posters: 1940's (Part 1), approximately 1940-1949 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Brochures, Pamphlets, Bulletins, Posters: 1940's (Part 2), approximately 1940-1949 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Brochures, Pamphlets, Bulletins, Posters: 1950's, approximately 1950-1959 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Brochures, Pamphlets, Bulletins, Posters: 1960's (Part 1), approximately 1960-1969 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Brochures, Pamphlets, Posters: 1960's (Part 2), approximately 1960-1969 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Brochures, Pamphlets, Posters: 1970's (Part 1), approximately 1970-1979 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Brochures, Pamphlets, Posters: 1970's (Part 2), approximately 1970-1979 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Brochures, Pamphlets, Posters: 1980's (Part 1), approximately 1980-1989 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Brochures, Pamphlets, Posters: 1980's (Part 2), approximately 1980-1989 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Brochures, Pamphlets, Posters: 1990's, approximately 1990-1999 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Brochures, Pamphlets, Posters: 1990's (Part 2), approximately 1990-1999 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Brochures, Pamphlets, Posters: 1990's (Part 3), approximately 1990-1999 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Brochures, Pamphlets, Posters: 2000's (Part 1), approximately 2000-2010 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Brochures, Pamphlets, Posters: 2000's (Part 2), approximately 2000-2010 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Brochures, Pamphlets, Posters: 2008-2009 Head Start Program, approximately 2000-2009 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Welcome to Xavier brochure, 2006 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Brochures, Pamphlets, Posters: 2010's (Part 1), approximately 2010-2011 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Brochures, Pamphlets, Posters: 2010's (Part 2), approximately 2010-2011 (Box 6, Folder 2)